Hiroko Yamaji Frontend Engineer

hiroko@hirokoymj.com +81-80-8452-9789 Current place: Tokyo, Japan

US Status

Green Card

Skills

Front-end

- React.js
- Redux/Redux Toolkit
- React Hooks
- React Router v5/6
- JavaScript
- Apollo Client v3
- Material UI v4
- Lodash
- HTML5/CSS3/Sass
- Responsive Web Design
- REST API
- Google Map API

Back-end

- Node.js
- Typescript
- Apollo Server v3
- MongoDB Atlas
- Mongoose

Cloud Platform

- Google Cloud
- Heroku

Version Control

- Git commands
- GitLab

Software

- Visual Studio Code
- Apollo Studio
- Slack
- Google Meet
- Microsoft Teams
- JIRA
- Confluence
- Figma

I worked as Front-end engineer for 15 years in Los Angeles and recent 3 years in Japan. Since I will be returning to US, I am looking for Software Engineer position or Google Cloud related job. I am available to move in California, Arizona (Phoenix, Tempe) or Texas. My strong skill is React.js and GraphQL.

Code Sample:

https://www.hirokoymj.com

https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-web-frontend

Work Experience

Infosys <u>Limited Japan</u> Tokyo

May 2022 - Present

Google Cloud Technical Support (August 2022 – Present)

- Work in the platform team specialized in serverless, cloud database on Google Cloud.
- Reproduce customer's issues on a test cloud environment for troubleshooting.
- Organize the cause of issue and reporting the details to a customer using soft skills.

Frontend Engineer (May 2022 – August 2022)

- Architected a new web application using React, Redux and i18n for Japanese life insurance company.
- Japanese language support for offshore members.

Asurion Japan Tokyo

May 2021 – January 2022

Frontend Engineer (Contractor)

- Used React.js, TypeScript and GraphQL.
- Developed a new feature for the call center web app.
- Performed React component testing by Cypress.

HyreCar Inc. Los Angeles, CA

January 2019 – December 2020

Software Engineer

- Developed Owner web application using React.js and GraphQL.
- Joined a small IT team and worked with other developers and a UI designer.
- 90% of my daily work was the coding including a pull request by Git commands.

Beachbody.com Santa Monica, CA December 2017 – September 2018

Frontend Engineer

- Build responsive web pages using grid system in Bootstrap 3.
- Embedded a workout video and built image carousel using JavaScript.

Strategic Partners Inc. Northridge, CA

December 2016 - June 2017

Frontend Engineer

- Converted a non-responsive website to a responsive using Bootstrap 3.
- Created a weather info component by OpenWeather API using JavaScript.

Teleflora.com Los Angeles, CA

October 2009 - October 2016

Frontend Developer

- JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap3
- Built responsive landing pages for Teleflora.com e-commerce site.

MC Squared Los Angeles, CA September 2006 – November 2007

Web Developer (Full Stack)

• Built websites from scratch for high-end condominiums under construction.

Sony Electronics Inc. Santa Monica, CA July 2005 – July 2006 Web Developer (Contractor)

Education

Santa Monica College Santa Monica, CA February 2004 - June 2005

Certificate of Interactive Media

Yamawaki Gakuten Junior College Tokyo, Japan April 1989 – March 1991

Associate of Arts in Food Science

Certifications

Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect
Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Database Engineer
July 2023

• Google Certified Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer January 2023